Guide to the Benjamin Nelson Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Benjamin Nelson Papers
1925-1977.
Nelson, Benjamin, 1911-1977.
106 linear ft. (224 document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book & Manuscript Library Butler Library, 6th Fl. East, 535 West 114th St., New York, NY. 10027
MS#1485
4079151
Biographical Note
Historian, sociologist. Nelson taught at City College of New York, the University of Chicago, the University of Minnesota, Columbia University, Hofstra College, S.U.N.Y. Stony Brook, and The New School for Social Research. He also edited special issues of Psychoanalysis and the Psychoanalytic Review and acted as an advisor for Harper & Row and other publishers.
Scope and Content
Professional and personal correspondence, manuscripts and notes for his many publications in the social sciences and Renaissance studies, drafts and notes for his The Idea of Usury and writings about Max Weber, other papers collected during his teaching career, and materials for the many professional conferences which he attended and for the academic associations and societies in which he was active.
Arrangement
Material is arranged into four series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: General Alphabetical Files
Series III: Conferences, 1950-1978
Series IV: Manuscripts and Notes
Subjects
Harper & Row, Publishers.; University of Chicago--Faculty.; University of Minnesota--Faculty.; Columbia University--Faculty.; Hofstra College--Faculty.; State University of New York at Stony Brook--Faculty.; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.)--Faculty.; Weber, Max, 1864-1920.; Social sciences.; Renaissance--Study and teaching.; Scholarly publishing.; Publishers and publishing.; Psychoanalysis--Periodicals.; Usury.; Historians.; Sociologists.; College teachers.; Editors.; Psychoanalysis and the psychoanalytic review.
Acquisition
1978 M-78 Nelson, Marie Coleman Gift
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Aptheker, Herbert (Box 1)
  - Arendt, Hannah (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Brooks (Box 1)
  - Barzun, Jacques (Box 1)
  - Bellow, Saul (Box 1)
  - Bentley, Eric Russell (Box 1)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno (Box 1)
  - Bronowski, Jacob (Box 1)
  - Brophy, Brigid Antonia (Box 1)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth (Box 1)
  - Cousins, Norman (Box 1)
  - Cox, Archibald (Box 1)
  - David, Robert Gorham (Box 1)
  - Erikson, Erik Homburger (Box 1)
  - Ernst, Morris Leopold (Box 1)
  - Farrell, James Thomas (Box 1)
  - Ford, Charles Henri (Box 1)
  - Goodman, Paul (Box 1)
  - Hardwick, Elizabeth (Box 2)
  - Hayes, Carlton Joseph Huntley (Box 2)
  - Howe, Irving (Box 2)
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Alvin Saunders (Box 2)
  - Kailen, Horace Meyer (Box 2)
  - Kazin, Alfred (Box 2)
  - Kennan, George Frost (Box 2)
  - Levi-Strauss, Claude (Box 2)
  - Macdonald, Dwight (Box 2)
  - Mannheim, Karl (Box 2)
  - Menninger, Karl August us (Box 2)
  - Montagu, Ashley (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 2)
  - Needham, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Podhoretz, Norman (Box 2)
  - Randall, John Herman, Jr. (Box 2)
  - Ransom, John Crowe (Box 2)
  - Reik, Theodor (Box 2)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt (Mrs. F.D.) (Box 2)
  - Salvemini, Gaetaho (Box 2)
  - Schapiro, Meyer (Box 2)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, Jr. (Box 2)
  - Schwartz, Delmore (Box 2)
  - Sontag, Susan (Box 2)
  - Stevenson, Adlai Ewing (Box 2)
  - Tawney, Richard Henry (Box 2)
  - Toynbee, Arnold Joseph (Box 2)
  - Trevor-Roper, Hugh Redwald (Box 2)
  - Trilling, Lionel (Box 2)
  - Wilson, Edmund (Box 2)
- Series II: General Alphabetical Files
  - A (Box 3)
  - Al (Box 3)
  - Aanenestad, Elling (Box 3)
  - Abdel-Malek, Anouar (Box 3)
  - Abraxas: Journal for the Theoretical Study of Philosophy and the Humanities (Box 3)
  - Adams, James Luther (Box 3)
  - Adler, Nathan (Box 3)
  - Adler Foreign Books (Box 3)
  - Africa, Thomas W. (Box 3)
  - Albert, Hans (Box 3)
  - Allport, Gordon W. (Box 3)
  - Am (Box 4)
  - American… (Societies) (Box 4)
  - American Anthropological Association (Box 4)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 4)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) (Box 4)
  - American Historical Association (Box 4)
  - American Jewish Committee (Box 4)
  - American Journal of Sociology (Box 4)
  - American Society for the Study of Religion (Box 4)
  - American Society of Church History (Box 4)
  - American Sociological Association (Box 4)
  - American Sociological Society (Box 4)
  - Ammons, Carol H. (Box 4)
  - An -- Au (Box 5)
  - Anastos, Milton V. (Box 5)
  - The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science (Box 5)
  - Apple, Lawrence (Box 5)
  - Archive for Reformation History (Box 5)
  - Argosy Book Stores (Box 5)
  - Arno Press (Box 5)
  - ARC: Society for the Arts, Religion and Contemporary Culture, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Askew, Melvin W. (Box 5)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies (Box 5)
  - B (Box 6)
  - Ba-Ban (Box 6)
  - Bacon, Edmund N. (Box 6)
  - Baker, Kenneth A. (Box 6)
  - Balfe, Judith H. (Box 6)
  - Bar… (Box 6)
  - Barker, Bernard (Box 6)
  - Barbero, Yves (Box 6)
  - Barrett, William (Box 6)
  - Barclay, James Ralph (Box 6)
  - Barkun, Michael (Box 6)
  - Barnes & Noble, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Baron, Salo W. (Box 6)
  - Baron, Samuel H. (Box 6)
  - Basic Books (Box 6)
  - Bas-Baz (Box 6)
  - Be-Ben (Box 7)
  - Beacon Press (Box 7)
  - Beer, Abraham (Box 7)
  - Bell, Daniel (Box 7)
  - Bell, Nora M. (Box 7)
  - Bell, John M. (Box 7)
  - Bellah, Robert N. (Box 7)
  - Belohradsky, Vaclav (Box 7)
  - Bendix, Reinhard (Box 7)
  - Benton, John F. (Box 7)
  - Ber-Bez (Box 7)
  - Berger, Peter L. (Box 7)
  - Berger, Stephen David (Box 7)
  - Bergin, James F. (Box 7)
  - Bernert, Christopher (Box 7)
  - Berrios, Lizardo (Box 7)
  - Bi (Box 8)
  - Bierer, Joshua (Box 8)
  - Bierstadt, Robert (Box 8)
  - Birnbaum, Norman (Box 8)
  - Bl (Box 8)
  - Blackman, Allan (Box 8)
  - Blanchard, William H. (Box 8)
  - Bland, Robert (Box 8)
  - Blauner, Robert (Box 8)
  - Bloom, Solomon (Box 8)
  - Blum, Fred H. (Box 8)
  - Blumenberg, Hans (Box 8)
  - Bo (Box 9)
  - Boeira, Nelson Fernando (Box 9)
  - Bokser, Ben Zion (Box 9)
  - Bonifazi, Conrad (Box 9)
  - Borkin, Joseph (Box 9)
  - Bosworth, Stanley (Box 9)
  - Bourg, Carroll J. (Box 9)
  - Boyers, Robert (Box 9)
    (editor of Salmagundi )
  - Bozeman, Adda B. (Box 9)
  - Br (Box 10)
  - Brady, Sister Cora (Box 10)
  - Bram, Jean and Joseph (Box 10)
  - Brand, Gerd (Box 10)
  - Brandeis University (Box 10)
  - Brandt, Lewis W. (Box 10)
  - Braude, Beatrice (Box 10)
  - Braziller, George, Inc. (Box 10)
  - Brody, Robert D. (Box 10)
  - Broughton, Shirley (Box 10)
  - Brown, Lillian (Box 10)
  - Brown, Richard H. (Box 10)
  - Browning, Donald (Box 10)
  - Brundage, James A. (Box 10)
  - Bu-By (Box 10)
  - Buchler, Justis (Box 10)
  - Buck, Roger C. (Box 10)
  - Byrne, Eugene H. (Box 10)
  - C (Box 11)
  - Ca (Box 11)
  - Cahnman, Werner J. (Box 11)
  - Calhoun, Donald W. (Box 11)
  - Cambridge University Press (Box 11)
  - Carmichael, Joel (Box 11)
  - Carterette, E.C. and Martha (Box 11)
  - Caruth, Elaine (Box 11)
  - Casanova, Jose V. (Box 11)
  - Ce (Box 11)
  - Ch (Box 12)
  - Charlier, Roger H (Box 12)
  - Chang, Chung-ying (Box 12)
  - Cheng, Ronald Ye-lin (Box 12)
  - Chicago, University of (Box 12)
  - Chicago, The University of Chicago Press (Box 12)
  - Childers, Marjorie (Box 12)
  - Chilton Book Company (Box 12)
  - Chodak, Szymon (Box 12)
  - Choi, Chaanshik (Box 12)
  - Choron, Jacques (Box 12)
  - Christmas Cards (Box 12)
  - Ci (Box 13)
  - Cl (Box 13)
  - Claremont, School of Theology at (Box 13)
  - Clark, Martin (Box 13)
  - Clark, Walter Houston (Box 13)
  - Co-Coh (Box 13)
  - Cohen, Arthur A. (Box 13)
  - Cohen, Boaz (Box 13)
  - Cohen, Felix S. (Box 13)
  - Cohen, Morris R. (Box 13)
  - Cohen, Robert S (Box 13)
  - Col… (Box 13)
  - College Entrance Examination Board (Box 13)
  - Columbia University (Box 14)
  - Com-Con (Box 15)
  - Commentary (Box 15)
  - Coo-Coz (Box 15)
  - Cook, Edward F. (Box 15)
  - Cooper, Russell M. (Box 15)
  - Cooperman, David (Box 15)
  - Cornell University Press (Box 15)
  - Couch, William T. (Box 15)
  - Courtenay, William J. (Box 15)
  - Cr-Cy (Box 15)
  - Cross, William M. (Box 15)
  - Cuddihy, John Murray (Box 15)
  - Cunningham, Michael (Box 15)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd. (Box 15)
  - D (Box 16)
  - Da (Box 16)
  - Daedalus (Box 16)
  - Daniels, Patricia (Box 16)
  - Daniels, Wilbur (Box 16)
  - Danto, Arthur C. (Box 16)
  - D’Antonio, William V. (Box 16)
  - Dauber and Pine Bookshops, Inc. (Box 16)
  - Davis, Wallace Martin (Box 16)
  - Daly, John Lawrence (Box 16)
  - Daly, Robert W. (Box 16)
  - De (Box 17)
  - DeGrazia, Alfred (Box 17)
  - DeJesus, Pedro (Box 17)
  - Denitch, Bogdan (Box 17)
  - de Roover, Raymond and Florence E. (Box 17)
  - Desmonde, William H. (Box 17)
  - Deutsche gesekkschaft fur Soziologie (Box 17)
  - Deutscher, Irwin (Box 17)
  - Dh (Box 18)
  - D’Heilly, Jean-Louis (Box 18)
  - Dhondt, J. (Box 18)
  - Di (Box 18)
  - Diamond, Stanley (Box 18)
  - DiLiscia, Michel (Box 18)
  - Dittes, James E. (Box 18)
  - Do (Box 18)
  - Doherty, Joseph E. (Box 18)
  - Donagan, Alan (Box 18)
  - Douglas, Jack D. (Box 18)
  - Dr-Dy (Box 18)
  - Drouberger, Ilse (Box 18)
  - Dumont, Louis (Box 18)
  - Duncan, Hugh Dalziel (Box 18)
  - E -- Ed (Box 19)
  - Early, Sarah (Box 19)
  - Eastern Sociological Society (Box 19)
  - The Economic History Association (Box 19)
  - Edel, Abraham and Mary (Box 19)
  - Ef-El (Box 19)
  - Effrat, Andrew (Box 19)
  - Egan, Robert (Box 19)
  - Eisenbud, Jule (Box 19)
  - Eisenstadt, S.N. (Box 19)
  - Eisenstein, Elizabeth L. (Box 19)
  - Eissler, K.R. (Box 19)
  - Eister, Allan W. (Box 19)
  - Eliade, Mircea (Box 19)
  - Elkana, Yehuda (Box 19)
  - Ellenberger, Henri F. (Box 19)
  - Elton, W.R. (Box 19)
  - Em-Ez (Box 20)
  - Emery, Richard W (Box 20)
  - Encounter (Box 20)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica (Box 20)
  - Endelman, Robert (Box 20)
  - Enzer, Hyman A (Box 20)
  - The Ethical Culture Society of Long Island (Box 20)
  - Etzkowitz, Henry (Box 20)
  - Evans, Austin Patterson (Box 20)
  - Evans, William M (Box 20)
  - Everett, John Rutherford (Box 20)
  - F (Box 21)
  - Fa (Box 21)
  - Faber, Mel D. (Box 21)
  - Fabian, Ilona, H. (Box 21)
  - Fantel, Hans (Box 21)
  - Farber, Leslie H. (Box 21)
  - Fe (Box 21)
  - Feldblum, Mary (Box 21)
  - Fell, Joseph P. (Box 21)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence (Box 21)
  - Ferrarotti, Franco (Box 21)
  - Fertig, Howard (Box 21)
  - Fetscher, Iring (Box 21)
  - Feuer, Lewis S. (Box 21)
  - Fi (Box 22)
  - Fielder, Leslie A. (Box 22)
  - Fince, Henry Albert and Nydia (Box 22)
  - Fine, Reuben (Box 22)
  - Fingarette, Herbert (Box 22)
  - Finely, Moses J. (Box 22)
  - Fischer-Barnicol, Hans A. and Dora (Box 22)
  - Fisk, Franklin G. (Box 22)
  - Fitzgerald, James L. (Box 22)
  - Fl-Fo (Box 23)
  - Flack, Michael J. (Box 23)
  - Ford, Joseph Brandon (Box 23)
  - Francher, J. Scott (Box 23)
  - Franke, Herbert (Box 23)
  - Franklin, Burt (Box 23)
  - Franklin, Norman (Box 23)
  - Fr (Box 23)
  - The Free Press (Box 23)
  - Friess, Horace L. (Box 23)
  - Fu-Fy (Box 23)
  - Fybish, Ira (Box 23)
  - G (Box 24)
  - Ga (Box 24)
  - Gallagher, John F. (Box 24)
  - Gallagher, John J. (Box 24)
  - García-Gómez, Jorge (Box 24)
  - Garlin, Edwin N. (Box 24)
  - Gaster, Theodor H. (Box 24)
  - Ge (Box 24)
  - Geiger, Theodore and Frances (Box 24)
  - Gelber, Sidney and Anita (Box 24)
  - Geraghty, Michael (Box 24)
  - Gi (Box 25)
  - Gianturco, Elio (Box 25)
  - Gilmore, William J. (Box 25)
  - Gingerich, Owen (Box 25)
  - Ginsburg, Gerald (Box 25)
  - Gioscia, Victor (Box 25)
  - Gist, Noel P. (Box 25)
  - Gittins, John (Box 25)
  - Gittleman, Jerome (Box 25)
  - Gl (Box 26)
  - Glazier, Ira A. (Box 26)
  - Glenn, Michael L. (Box 26)
  - Glock, Charles Y. (Box 26)
  - Go (Box 26)
  - Goldenhar, Francine (Box 26)
  - Goldman, Steven Louis (Box 26)
  - Goodman, Percival (Box 26)
  - Goodberg, Paul J. (Box 26)
  - Goodman, Alice and Mortimer (Box 26)
  - Goodman, Donald F. (Box 26)
  - Goodman, Naomi Ascher and Rachel (Box 26)
  - Goodman, Sally (Box 26)
  - Goodman, Susan (Box 26)
  - Gosselin, Edward A. (Box 26)
  - Goodman, Paul (Box 27)
  - Gr -- Gs (Box 28)
  - Greenbaum, Joseph J. (Box 28)
  - Greenwood Press (Box 28)
  - Grene, Marjorie (Box 28)
  - Gu (Box 28)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box 28)
  - Gurevitz, Salik (Box 28)
  - Gustin, Bernard H. (Box 28)
  - H (Box 29)
  - Ha (Box 29)
  - Hacker, Frederick J. (Box 29)
  - Hadden, Jeffrey K. (Box 29)
  - Hajda, Jan (Box 29)
  - Hajjdar, Ted (Box 29)
  - Halberstam, Aron (Box 29)
  - Hall, Robert L. (Box 29)
  - Hammond, Phillip E. (Box 29)
  - Hanly, Charles (Box 29)
  - Hanson, Norwood Russell (Box 29)
  - Harcourt, Brace Jovanovitch, Inc. (Box 29)
  - Harder, Theodor (Box 29)
  - Harisi, Mahmud S. (Box 29)
  - Harris, F. Gentry (Box 29)
  - Harvard University (Box 29)
  - Harwood, Britton J. (Box 29)
  - Hayes, Richard A. (Box 29)
  - Harper & Row (Box 30)
    - General (Box 30)
    - A-C (Box 31)
    - D-J (Box 32)
    - J-O (Box 33)
    - P (Box 34)
    - Q -- R (Box 35)
    - Royalties (Box 35)
    - Royalties (Box 36)
    - S-V (Box 37)
    - Van Dusen, Hugh (Box 38)
    - Van Dusen, Hugh (Box 39)
    - Van Dusen-Z (Box 40)
  - He (Box 41)
  - Heelan, Patrick A. (Box 41)
  - Heldman, Marilyn Eiseman (Box 41)
  - Helle, Horst J. (Box 41)
  - Hellman, C. Doris (Box 41)
  - Henle, Mary (Box 41)
  - Hexter, J.H. (Box 41)
  - Hi (Box 41)
  - Hiebert, Margaret (Box 41)
  - Hillel Foundation (Box 41)
  - Hinkle, Giselda and Rosco (Box 41)
  - History and Theory (Box 41)
  - History of the behavioral Sciences Newsletter (Box 41)
  - Ho (Box 42)
  - Hofstra (Box 42)
  - Holt, John R. (Box 42)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc. (Henry Holt and Co., Inc.) (Box 42)
  - Holzner, Burkart (Box 42)
  - Homans, Peter (Box 42)
  - Hopper, Stanley R. (Box 42)
  - Hora, Thomas (Box 42)
  - Horkheimer, Max (Box 42)
  - Horowitz, Irving Louis (Box 42)
  - Horowitz, Michael (Box 42)
  - Hoselitz, Bert (Box 42)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company (Box 42)
  - Hsu, Michael (Box 42)
  - Hu-Hy (Box 43)
  - Hurwitz, Samuel (Box 43)
  - Hyman, Arthur (Box 43)
  - I-Ins (Box 43)
  - Ideal Book Store (Box 43)
  - Institute of Intercultural Research (Box 43)
  - Int-Iz (Box 43)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 43)
  - International Sociological Association (Box 43)
  - Isis (Box 43)
  - Huff, Toby (Box 44)
  - The International Society for the Comparative Study of Civilizations (ISCSC) (Box 45)
    - General (Box 45)
    - A (Box 46)
    - Activities (Box 46)
    - Applications and Roster (Box 46)
    - B (Box 46)
    - Bibliographies (Box 46)
    - Bills (Box 46)
    - Book Exhibits (Box 46)
    - Book Reviews (Box 46)
    - Brochures (Box 46)
    - Bulletin Correspondence (Box 46)
    - C (Box 46)
    - Call for Papers (Box 46)
    - Canadian SCSC (Box 46)
    - Council (Box 46)
    - D (Box 46)
    - E (Box 46)
    - F (Box 47)
    - Flack, Michael J. (Box 47)
    - Forms (Box 47)
    - G (Box 47)
    - H (Box 47)
    - Hall, Robert L. (Box 47)
    - Honorary Members (Box 47)
    - I (Box 47)
    - J (Box 47)
    - K (Box 47)
    - Kavolis, Vytautas (Box 47)
    - L (Box 48)
    - M (Box 48)
    - Meetings and Minutes (Box 48)
    - Meetings--Locations (Box 48)
    - Melko, Matthew (Box 48)
    - Membership (Box 48)
    - Mouton Publishers (Box 48)
    - N (Box 49)
    - Narroll, Raoul (Box 49)
    - Newsletter (Box 49)
    - Nominations (Box 49)
    - Non-members (Box 49)
    - O (Box 49)
    - P (Box 49)
    - Programs (Box 49)
    - Publicity (Box 49)
    - Q (Box 49)
    - R (Box 49)
    - Richardson, David B. (Box 49)
    - S (Box 50)
    - T (Box 50)
    - U-V (Box 50)
    - W (Box 50)
    - Wolf, Charles Parker (Box 50)
    - Y (Box 50)
    - Z (Box 50)
  - J (Box 51)
  - Ja-Je (Box 51)
  - Jacobs, Norman (Box 51)
  - Jacobson, David C. (Box 51)
  - Jacoby, E.G. (Box 51)
  - Jager, Edward C. (Box 51)
  - Janowitz, Henry D. and Aadis (Box 51)
  - Janowitz, Morris (Box 51)
  - The Jewish Publication Society of America (Box 51)
  - Jo-Ju (Box 52)
  - Johnson, Benton (Box 52)
  - Johnson, Frank A. (Box 52)
  - Jonas, Hans (Box 52)
  - Jonassohn, Kurt (Box 52)
  - Jones, Robert Alum (Box 52)
  - Jones, Thomas Evans (Box 52)
  - Joseph, Barbara (Box 52)
  - Journal of Religion (Box 52)
  - Journal of the History of Ideas (Box 52)
  - The Journal of the History of Sociology (Box 52)
  - Jung, Richard (Box 52)
  - Jurgens, Johanna (Box 52)
  - K (Box 53)
  - Ka (Box 53)
  - Kadushin, Charles (Box 53)
  - Kakulski, Daniel Joseph (Box 53)
  - Kalberg, Stephen (Box 53)
  - Kalin, Eugene B. (Box 53)
  - Kallen, Horace Meyer (Box 53)
  - Kamp, Casper (Box 53)
  - Kaprow, Allan (Box 53)
  - Kasler, Dirk (Box 53)
  - Kassalow, Everett and Sylvia (Box 53)
  - Kavolis, Vytautas (Box 54)
  - Kay, Jeffrey Lawrence (Box 54)
  - Ke (Box 54)
  - Keen, J. Ernest (Box 54)
  - Kelley, Donald R. (Box 54)
  - Kendler, Bernhard (Box 54)
  - Kent, Caron and Vera (Box 54)
  - Kenyon, Dorothy (Box 54)
  - Kerr, David H. (Box 54)
  - Kh-Ki (Box 55)
  - Kim, Hei Chu (Box 55)
  - King, Kenneth (Box 55)
  - Kirshner, Julius (Box 55)
  - Kisch, Guido (Box 55)
  - Kitagawa, Joseph M. (Box 55)
  - Kl (Box 55)
  - Klaaren, Eugene M. (Box 55)
  - Klausner, Samuel Lundel (Box 55)
  - Kleinhaus, Robert G. (Box 55)
  - Klima, Rolf (Box 55)
  - Kn (Box 55)
  - Ko (Box 55)
  - Kobrin, David (Box 55)
  - Kohler, Oskar (Box 55)
  - Kohn, Jerome H. (Box 55)
  - Konig, Rene (Box 55)
  - Korsch, Hedda (Box 55)
  - Kovel, Joel (Box 55)
  - Koyre, Alexandre (Box 55)
  - Kr (Box 56)
  - Krader, Lawrence (Box 56)
  - Kramer, Leon (Box 56)
  - Krass, Alfred C. (Box 56)
  - Kraus, Hans P. (Box 56)
  - Kriss, Gary (Box 56)
  - Kristeller, Paul Oskar (Box 56)
  - Kristol, Irving (Box 56)
  - Kroening, Vernm (Box 56)
  - Ku (Box 56)
  - Kubie, Lawrence S. (Box 56)
  - Kursh, Charlotte Olmsted (Box 56)
  - Kuttner, Stephan (Box 56)
  - L (Box 57)
  - La (Box 57)
  - Ladner, Gerhart B. (Box 57)
  - Lagey, Joseph C. (Box 57)
  - Lakatos, Imre (Box 57)
  - Lalande, André (Box 57)
  - La Lumia, Joseph (Box 57)
  - Landynski, Jacob (Box 57)
  - Lang, Kurt (Box 57)
  - Lanternari, Vittorio (Box 57)
  - Lardé, Roger G. (Box 57)
  - Larrea, Jose Maria Gayarre (Box 57)
  - Laske, Otto Ernest (Box 57)
  - Lasky, Melvin J. (Box 57)
  - Lasswell, Harold J. (Box 57)
  - Last, Walter Allan (Box 57)
  - Laszlo, Ervin (Box 57)
  - Lawrence, Beth (Box 57)
  - Lawrence, Charles (Box 57)
  - Le (Box 58)
  - Leathers, Michael J. (Box 58)
  - Leeds, Anthony (Box 58)
  - Leites, Edmund (Box 58)
  - LeMay, Richard (Box 58)
  - Leonard, Richard W. (Box 58)
  - Lepenies, Wolf (Box 58)
  - Lepsius, M. Rainer (Box 58)
  - Letendre, Marie-Louise (Box 58)
  - Levine, Donald Nathan (Box 58)
  - Levine, Hillel (Box 58)
  - Li (Box 59)
  - Liben, Meyer and Diana (Box 59)
  - Lilienfeld, Robert (Box 59)
  - Lin, Robert (Box 59)
  - The Lindisfarne Association (Box 59)
  - Lipman, Eugene J. (Box 59)
  - Lippincott, Benjamin Evans and Gertrude Lawton (Box 59)
  - J.B. Lippincott Company (Box 59)
  - The Living Theatre (Box 59)
  - Lo (Box 59)
  - Long Island Lighting Company (Box 59)
  - Long Island Philosophic Society (Box 59)
  - Lopez, Robert S. (Box 59)
  - Lopez-Reyes, Ramon R. (Box 59)
  - Loubser, Jan J. (Box 59)
  - Louerde, Lorin B. (Box 59)
  - Lowenthal, Leo (Box 59)
  - Löwith, Karl (Box 59)
  - Lu (Box 60)
  - Luckham, A.R. (Box 60)
  - Ludz, Peter Christian (Box 60)
  - Luhmann, Niklas (Box 60)
  - Ly (Box 60)
  - Lyman, Stanford Morris (Box 60)
  - M (Box 61)
  - Ma-Mac (Box 61)
  - McCartney, James R. (Box 61)
  - McCloskey, David Daniel (Box 61)
  - McConica, James M. (Box 61)
  - Macdonald, Dwight (Box 61)
  - McGee, Ruth (Mrs. Phillip H.) (Box 61)
  - McGlone, Gerry (Box 61)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company (Box 61)
  - Mack, Arien (Box 61)
  - McKeon, Richard P.McKnight, Stephen A. (Box 61)
  - McLaughlin, Mary Martin (Box 61)
  - The Macmillan CompanyMcMullin, Ernan (Box 61)
  - Mad-Man (Box 62)
  - Maier, Joseph and Alice (Box 62)
  - Mandelbaum, Maurice (Box 62)
  - Mar-Maz (Box 62)
  - Marcus, John T. (Box 62)
  - Marsak, Leonard (Box 62)
  - Martin, David (Box 62)
  - Maschler, Chaninah (Box 62)
  - Max Planck Institut (Box 62)
  - May, Rollo (Box 62)
  - Mazlish, Bruce (Box 62)
  - Me (Box 63)
  - Meadows, Paul (Box 63)
  - The Mediaeval Academy of America (Box 63)
  - The Medieval Club of New York (Box 63)
  - Meerloo, Joost A.M. (Box 63)
  - Meinke, Robert J. (Box 63)
  - Melko, Matthew (Box 63)
  - Merideth, Robert (Box 63)
  - Merlan, Philip and Franciszka (Box 63)
  - Merton, Robert K. (Box 63)
  - Mesthene, Emmanuel G. (Box 63)
  - Meyer, Isidore S. (Box 63)
  - Meyerhoff, Hans (Box 63)
  - Mi (Box 64)
  - Michigan, University of Press (Box 64)
  - Miles, Matthew B. (Box 64)
  - Miller, James S. (Box 64)
  - Millman, Robert D. (Box 64)
  - Minnesota, University of (Box 64)
  - Mitscherlich, Alexander (Box 64)
  - Mitzman, Arthur (Box 64)
  - Mladen, Leo Mucha (Box 64)
  - Mo (Box 65)
  - Mok, Albert L. (Box 65)
  - Moller, Herbert (Box 65)
  - Moore, John C. (Box 65)
  - Moore, John Robert (Box 65)
  - Mora, George (Box 65)
  - Moravia, Sergio (Box 65)
  - Morgan, Edmund Sears (Box 65)
  - Morgenroth, Estelle (Box 65)
  - Morin, Alexander J. (Box 65)
  - Morris, James W. (Box 65)
  - Morrow, Felix (Box 65)
  - Morse, Richard McGee (Box 65)
  - Mosier, Richard D. (Box 65)
  - Moskowitz, Stanley (Box 65)
  - Mu-My (Box 66)
  - Muchnick, David M. (Box 66)
  - Muller, Gert H. (Box 66)
  - Munakata, Iwao (Box 66)
  - Mundy, John H. and Charlotte W. (Box 66)
  - Munk, Erika (Box 66)
  - Murdoch, John E. (Box 66)
  - Murvar, Vatro (Box 66)
  - Na-Nas (Box 66)
  - Naftalin, Arthur E. (Box 66)
  - Nagourney, Herbert (Box 66)
  - Nandan, Yash (Box 66)
  - Nash, Cerille Miller (Box 66)
  - Nat --Naz (Box 67)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 67)
  - National Planning Association (Box 67)
  - National Psychological Association for Psychologists, Inc. (Box 67)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 67)
  - Naughton, Frank (Box 67)
  - Nelson, Benjamin (Box 68)
    - Activities and Publicity (Box 68)
    - Grants and Fellowships (Box 69)
    - Personal and Financial Papers (Box 70)
  - Nelson, Benjamin N. (Box 71)
    (cousin)
  - Nelson, Eleanor Rackow (Box 71)
  - Nelson, Jack and Diana (Box 71)
  - Nelson, Leon George and Edwina (Box 71)
  - Nelson, Marie Alma Louise Poole Coleman Miller (Box 71)
  - Melson, Marks (Box 71)
  - Nelson, Mary F (Box 72)
    - Correspondence; Typescripts; Mss (Box 72)
    - Mss (Box 73)
    - Clippings and Books (Box 74)
  - Ne (Box 75)
  - Nelson, Hart M. (Box 75)
  - Nelson Family (Box 75)
  - Neumaier, John J. (Box 75)
  - Neusner, Jacob (Box 75)
  - New Directions (Box 75)
  - New School for Social Research (Box 76)
    - General (Box 76)
    - A (Box 77)
    - C (Box 77)
    - Courses (Box 77)
    - Culture (Box 77)
    - Czerna, Daria (Box 77)
    - D (Box 77)
    - Dissertations (Box 77)
    - F (Box 78)
    - Giuca, Philip V. (Box 78)
    - Greenbaum, Joseph J. (Box 78)
    - Greenberg, H. (Box 78)
    - Greene, Murray (Box 78)
    - Hickey, Pat (Box 78)
    - History of Ideas (Box 78)
    - Hosiosky, Issai (Box 78)
    - Independent Study (Box 78)
    - “Leaves” (Box 78)
    - Library (Box 78)
    - Licausse, Vincent (Box 78)
    - M (Box 79)
    - M.A. Exams (Box 79)
    - M.A.L.S. (Box 79)
    - Meyer, Carol--Memorial Seminar (Box 79)
    - Meetings (Box 79)
    - Methodology (Box 79)
    - Oral Exams (Box 79)
    - P (Box 79)
    - Personal (Box 79)
    - Ph.D. (Box 79)
    - Reading Lists (Box 80)
    - Reimbursement (Travel and Reprints) (Box 80)
    - S (Box 80)
    - Signer, Esther (Box 80)
    - Social Science (Box 80)
    - Sociology (Box 80)
    - Steerman, W. (Box 80)